<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<configuration>
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.kerberos.principal</name>
        <value>gpadmin/_HOST@EXAMPLE.COM</value>
        <description>Kerberos principal pxf service should use. _HOST is replaced automatically with hostnames FQDN</description>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.kerberos.keytab</name>
        <value>${pxf.base}/keytabs/pxf.service.keytab</value>
        <description>Kerberos path to keytab file owned by pxf service with permissions 0400</description>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.user.impersonation</name>
        <value>true</value>
        <description>End-user identity impersonation, set to true to enable, false to disable</description>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.kerberos.constrained-delegation</name>
        <value>false</value>
        <description>
            Makes user impersonation work via Kerberos constrained delegation based on S4U2Self/Proxy Kerberos extension.
            This method does not require the PXF principal to be a Hadoop proxy user, but requires the S4U2 feature
            to be enabled in an Active Directory / IPA Server. Additional configuration is needed in the
            Active Directory / IPA Server to enable the PXF principal to impersonate end users.
            Set to true to enable, false to disable.
        </description>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.kerberos.ticket-renew-window</name>
        <value>0.8</value>
        <description>
            By default, PXF refreshes the Kerberos ticket when 80% (0.8) of its lifespan has elapsed.
            Specifies the window, as a float, at which PXF will actively refresh the ticket. This value
            must be between 0 and 1. Setting this value to 0 means that every PXF request will get a new
            ticket.
        </description>
    </property>

    <!--
    <property>
        <name>pxf.service.user.name</name>
        <value>${user.name}</value>
        <description>

            Uncomment and set the proper value only if:

            - user impersonation is enabled and you want to use the specified
              user as a proxy on the unsecured Hadoop clusters. This is useful
              when a proxy user has already been configured on the Hadoop side,
              and you don't want to add gpadmin (the default) as a proxy user.

            - user impersonation is disabled and you want queries from all
              Greenplum users to appear on the Hadoop side as coming from the
              specified user.

        </description>
    </property>
    -->

    <!--
    <property>
        <name>pxf.fs.basePath</name>
        <value></value>
        <description>
            Sets the base path when constructing a file URI for read and write
            operations. This property MUST be configured for any server that
            accesses a file using a file:* profile.
        </description>
    </property>
    !-->

    <property>
        <name>pxf.ppd.hive</name>
        <value>true</value>
        <description>Specifies whether Predicate Pushdown feature is enabled for Hive profiles.</description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.sasl.connection.retries</name>
        <value>5</value>
        <description>
            Specifies the number of retries to perform when a SASL connection is refused by a Namenode
            due to 'GSS initiate failed' error.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.orc.write.decimal.overflow</name>
        <value>round</value>
        <description>
            Specifies behavior of the PXF ORC profiles when writing NUMERIC data that exceeds the maximum precision of 38. Valid values are error, round and ignore. The default value is round.
            If set to error, PXF will report an error, potentially leaving an incomplete dataset in the external system.
            If set to round, PXF will try to round the value to meet both precision and scale requirements, or report an error if the value cannot be rounded, potentially leaving an incomplete dataset in the external system.
            If set to ignore, PXF will try to round the value to meet only the precision requirement; otherwise PXF will write NULL instead of the value (as in previous PXF versions).
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.orc.write.timezone.utc</name>
        <value>true</value>
        <description>
            Specifies whether the PXF ORC writer should use UTC timezone when writing timestamp values.
            If set to false, the PXF ORC writer will use the local timezone of the PXF JVM instead.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.write.decimal.overflow</name>
        <value>round</value>
        <description>
            Specifies behavior of the PXF Parquet profiles when writing NUMERIC data that exceeds the maximum precision of 38. Valid values are error, round, and ignore. The default value is round.
            If set to error, PXF will report an error, potentially leaving an incomplete dataset in the external system.
            If set to round, PXF will try to round the value to meet both precision and scale requirements, or report an error if the value cannot be rounded, potentially leaving an incomplete dataset in the external system.
            If set to ignore, PXF will try to round the value to meet both precision and scale requirements; otherwise PXF will write NULL if the value cannot be rounded (as in previous PXF versions).
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.int64.timestamps</name>
        <value>false</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to false, timestamps will be written to Parquet as INT96.
            If the parameter is set to true, both TIMESTAMP and TIMESTAMPZ values will be written as INT64 with TimestampLogicalTypeAnnotation.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_INT64_TIMESTAMPS parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is false.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.local.pxf.timezone.write</name>
        <value>true</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to true, the TIMESTAMP value will be converted to UTC based on the local time zone of the JVM running the PXF service.
            For example, if the local JVM time zone is +03:00, and a timestamp 2005-10-03 15:05:15.123 is received from Greenplum, it will be converted to UTC as 2005-10-03 12:05:15.123 (- 3 hours).
            This converted value will then be written to the Parquet file.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_LOCAL_PXF_TIMEZONE_WRITE parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is true.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.local.pxf.timezone.read</name>
        <value>true</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to true, the TIMESTAMP value from the Parquet file will be converted to the local time zone of the JVM running the PXF service, and then sent to Greenplum.
            For example, if the local time zone of the JVM is +03:00 and the Parquet file contains the timestamp 2005-10-03 12:00:00.000, it will be converted to 2005-10-03 15:00:00.000 (+3 hours) before being sent to Greenplum.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_LOCAL_PXF_TIMEZONE_READ parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is true.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.logical.type.interval</name>
        <value>false</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to false, INTERVAL data type will be written to Parquet as FIXED_LEN_BYTE_ARRAY.
            If the parameter is set to true, INTERVAL data type will be written to Parquet as FIXED_LEN_BYTE_ARRAY with IntervalLogicalTypeAnnotation.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_LOGICAL_TYPE_INTERVAL parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is false.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.logical.type.time</name>
        <value>false</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to false, TIME data type will be written to Parquet as INT64.
            If the parameter is set to true, TIME data type will be written to Parquet as INT64 with TimeLogicalTypeAnnotation.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_LOGICAL_TYPE_TIME parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is false.
        </description>
    </property>

    <property>
        <name>pxf.parquet.use.logical.type.uuid</name>
        <value>false</value>
        <description>
            If the parameter is set to false, UUID data type will be written to Parquet as FIXED_LEN_BYTE_ARRAY.
            If the parameter is set to true, UUID data type will be written to Parquet as FIXED_LEN_BYTE_ARRAY with UUIDLogicalTypeAnnotation.
            This parameter is equivalent to the USE_LOGICAL_TYPE_UUID parameter, which is used when creating external tables.
            If the parameter is specified in both places, the external table setting has higher priority.
            Default value is false.
        </description>
    </property>

</configuration>
